<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Edt72</string>

    <string name="tituloTop">Undertale</string>
    <string name="tituloInf">Characters</string>

    <string name="toriel">Toriel Dreemurr</string>
    <string name="asgore">Asgore Dreemurr</string>
    <string name="alphys">Alphys</string>
    <string name="undyne">Undyne</string>
    <string name="sans">Sans</string>
    <string name="papyrus">Papyrus</string>
    <string name="flowey">Flowey</string>
    <string name="mettaton">Mettaton</string>
    <string name="muffet">Muffet</string>
    <string name="onionsan">Onion-san</string>

    <string name="bossMonsterPosition">Boss monster</string>
    <string name="blank" />
    <string name="color">Colors</string>
    <string name="npc">NPC</string>
    <string name="battleSpriteTxt">Battle sprite</string>
    <string name="FirePalabra">Fire</string>
    <string name="royalScientistPalabra">Royal scientist</string>
    <string name="constructionPalabra">Construction</string>
    <string name="experimentationPalabra">Experimentation</string>

    <string name="asgoreApparence">Asgore\'a apparence wants to ressemble a goat. He has broad shoulders, a bulky body, a golden blond mane/beard and two large curved horns.He wears a suit of armor, a purple cape with golden pauldrons, and a crown on top of his head. The weapon he uses in battle is a long, red trident adorned with a flower. Asgore is shown to be the biggest main character in the entire game. Towards the end of the game, Asgore appears to be more fat rather than broad-chested.</string>
    <string name="asgorePersonality">Asgore is a kind monster that enjoys gardening and, like his son, speaks in southern slang. He\'s reluctant to fight, since gives the protagonist to fight and visit the Underground before fight. If we trie to spare him, we could see he\'s very familiar and still loves his ex-wife.\n Since all the monsters look up at him for hope, he has a huge pressure on his shoulders and the idea of free all of them is the only thing that keeps him going. He feels guilt for all he did to get free but he\'s so engaged to the monsters that he calls \'his duty\'.\nAs we get further in the game, we get to see Asgore lives in the past since he\'s always visiting the same places everyday, probably still in denial because his son\'s death.</string>
    <string name="batallaDescAsgore">Unlike all the previous fights, MERCY button is destroyed and we\'re forced to use the FIGHT button.\n\n-Use \'Talk\', located in ACT button, threee times lowers Asgore\'s defense by 10 and Attack by 1, only if the player didn\'t kill anyone in the run\n\n-Eat \'Toriel\'s Butterscotch Pie\' (if the player didn\'t consume it before) drops Asgore\'s defense by 5 and Attack by 1</string>
    <string name="asgoreFireAttackDesc">Like Toriel, Asgore uses Fire attacks with a similar patterns of her.\n\n-Four waves of small fireballs move from the top of the screen, which curve in a double helix pattern.\n\n-Smaller waves of small fireballs that move down the middle of the screen are interspersed with massive clouds of projectiles that cover entire sides of the screen\n\n-Partial circles of fireballs that gradually spiral in around the Bullet Board.\nHis hands move along the sides of the screen, leaving behind large fireballs that move towards the protagonist\'s SOUL after all the bullets appear. \n\n-Rings of large fireballs fire from the top of the screen, gradually moving from one corner to the other</string>
    <string name="asgoreBackstoryTxt">King Asgore and Queen Toriel ruled the Underground for millennia after humans sealed the monsters Underground upon their defeat during the war. Toriel and Asgore later had a son, Asriel, and adopted the first human to fall into the Ruins.\nThe tragedy of his children\'s deaths led Asgore to declare war on humanity in a fit of anger. He swore to kill any human that fell into the Underground and planned to use their SOULs to break the barrier and destroy all humans. Toriel, disgusted with him, left New Home and returned to the Ruins.\nBefore the protagonist fell into the Underground, six more humans fell. They all died, and Asgore saved their SOULs for future use.</string>
    <string name="asgoreColorAttack">Like other monsters in the game, Asgore has also a color attack.\nAt the beginning of the attack, he will have a pattern of blue and orange in his eyes, followed by an attack of the pattern with his trident.\nBlue means stay still, while orange means move.</string>

    <string name="torielApparence">Toriel is a Boss Monster whose head resembles a white-furred Nubian Goat, structured with droopy ears and short horns. She has a pair of visible fangs and long eyelashes, and her irises have a dark red tint. She has an anthropomorphic body, with paws at the end of her limbs. She wears a long purple robe that displays the Delta Rune on her chest. Toriel is seen with her reading glasses, one instance being in her house when reading a book on snail facts.</string>
    <string name="torielPersonality">Toriel is a kind monster that acts as a protective mother figure for the protagonist. She employs tough love on the protagonist as well as Asgore. She cares for children and was excited to become a mother.\nShe enjoys cooking and bakes butterscotch-cinnamon pie as well as her favorite, snail pie.\nToriel has a playful side, as shown by her love of puns and bad jokes, and she even keeps a journal of puns.\nToriel is said to be intelligent and dreams of becoming a teacher</string>
    <string name="torielStory">Before the events of Undertale, she was married to King Asgore and had a son, Asriel. When the first human fell into the Underground, she adopted them as their child. The deaths of their two children pushed Asgore to declare war on humanity, and as a result, she left him and retreated to the Ruins.</string>
    <string name="toriFireAttack">Like Asgore, she has fire powers that manifest in various way. Both Dreemurr have similar attack pattern
                        \n\n- A paw appears at the top-left corner of the Bullet Board and sweeps in an arc to the top-right corner, leaving a trail of fireballs. When the paw reaches the other side of the board, the fireballs will launch towards the SOUL and bounce off of the walls. In later rounds, the attack contains a second paw that starts at the bottom-right corner and mirrors the first. This attack ends immediately if the SOUL touches either paw.
                        \n\n-Fire waves: Streams of fireballs fall from the top of the Bullet Board in a crisscrossing double-helix pattern and accumulate at the bottom. The streams have holes in the middle of them to dodge through, including two safe spots in both top corners. In the harder version of this attack, the Bullet Board is shorter, and fireballs are hovering at the sides.
                        \n\n-Fire helix: Thicker streams of fireballs, too thick to dodge through, but they do not sweep back and forth
                        \n\n-Faltering: Fireballs fall haphazardly from the top of the Bullet Board, but deliberately move away from the SOUL if they come close, making it impossible to take damage from this attack. If the protagonist\'s HP is 2 or less, Toriel uses this attack exclusively.</string>
    <string name="batallaDescToriel">This is the first boss fight in the game and you can either FIGHT, ACT or MERCY.\nToriel is the only boss that, if the player\'s HP reach 2, her attacks will avoid the player\'s soul to not kill them. Still, is possible she kills you but it\'s very difficult.\n\nIn MERCY button, you can flee, allowing you to go upstairs again but you still need to win Toriel\'s fight in one way or another to continue the game, or spare until she gives up.\n\nIf chosen FIGHT after she stops attacking (after using \'spare\' 11 times), she will die in 1 hit and have an unique dialogue.\n\nIn ACT button, the only options are \'Check\' and \'Talk\', but even if you use this won\'t advance the battle.</string>

    <string name="alphysApparence">Alphys is a yellow, reptilian monster of similar height to the protagonist. Her posture is somewhat hunched over. She has yellow scales, claws, and protruding teeth (which seem to vary between two and four depending which way she faces). Her feet have three toes while there are three fingers and a thumb on each of her hands. Her \"hair\" is designed into points facing the back of her head. She normally wears round glasses and a white lab coat. Her glasses do not cover her eyelashes.</string>
    <string name="alphysPersonality">Alphys is a nerdy, shy recluse with a fondness for human anime and manga. She has crushes on multiple characters (some mild, others more serious), but struggles to communicate her feelings.\nAlphys is filled with guilt and insecurities about herself and her accomplishments. After she accidentally created the Amalgamates while experimenting with determination, she told nobody and became deeply depressed and remorseful.</string>
    <string name="alphysStory">Before the events of Undertale, Undyne meets Alphys in the Garbage Dump and they become friends. Alphys accidentally creates the Amalgamates through experimenting with Determination in hopes of saving monsters that have fallen down. The protagonist is able to encounter them in the True Lab later in the game.</string>
    <string name="battleDescAlphys">She\'s only of the few characters that have a battle sprite but actually she doesn\'t fight. Instead, she\'s some kind of \'helper\' in her only battle, on Mettaton\'s contest.\nAlso, like Undyne and Papyrus, she also has various sprites for battle menus; the normal one and the date one</string>
    <string name="constructionAlphys">Since she\'s rather intelligent, she can upgrade old machines or create new ones, like Mettaton\'s body (box and humanoid)</string>
    <string name="experimentationAlphys">Being the royal scientist forces her to experiment with monsters, trying to inyect determination or do whatever to try free the monsters in the Underground.</string>

    <string name="undyneApparence">Undyne is a piscine, anthropomorphic monster. She has blue scales and a long red ponytail. She has red and blue fins on the sides of her head, and a pair of sharp, yellow, protruding teeth. She wears a red eye shadow and has an eyepatch on her left eye. She also wears a black tank top and jeans, but debuts in armor varying in light and dark shades of gray. Her eyes have black vertical pupils and yellow sclera. Undyne has no nose.</string>
    <string name="undynePersonality">Undyne is passionate about everything that she does. She acts quickly on her ideas and is steadfast in her beliefs. Though she wants to defeat the protagonist, she also tries to be fair and offers an explanation of how Green Mode works. Asgore taught her the value of pacifism, which is why Undyne sees the protagonist as \"a wimpy loser with a big heart.\" When the protagonist first encounters her, she fights to further Asgore\'s plan of collecting seven human SOULs but, if the protagonist shows mercy, Undyne just as quickly defends them from Asgore.\nShe loves to help others and mentors Shyren and Papyrus in various skills. Undyne dislikes puzzles, loves japes, and enjoys anime, an affinity she shares with her romantic interest, Alphys. Since Alphys told Undyne that anime is actually human history, Undyne regards human history as exciting and cool.\nOut of all encountered monsters, Undyne possesses the most Determination. She melts before her death, implying that her body cannot handle the amount of Determination she has.</string>
    <string name="undyneStory">What we know what happens to Undyne before of the events of the game is very vague. We know that she challenged Asgore when she was younger and after not begin able to land a hit on him, the king offered to train her, eventually making her head of the Royal Guard.\nWe also know that,sometime in the past, she met Alphys in the Garbage dump, and became friends. Alhpys also was the one to tell her about anime.\nAfter becoming head of the Royal Guard, Papyrus come to ask her to train him. She refused since it was night but since next day he was still here she agreed. She didn\'t want him to enter the Royal Guard; it\'s a way too cruel place to such a innocent skeleton and instead she teach him how to cook.</string>
    <string name="undyneAttTit1">Spear + Colours</string>
    <string name="undyneDescAtt1">She has multiple patterns and attacks depending of the soul\'s colour\n\n-When the soul is green, she throws arrows from all sides at the protagonist in Green mode, including specifically slow and fast moving arrows, as well as arrows that flip the orientation that they are approaching from\n\n-When the soul is red, she can restricts the Bullet Board to a minuscule box which launches spears upwards toward the protagonist in three columns, throw a volley of continuous spears at the protagonist on a larger Board.\nWhen changing to green to red, she throws a single spear to the soul.\n\nIn genocide mode, there\'s an exclusive attack: throws rings of spears which enclose on the protagonist while rotating. She has another version of this attack in which the spears do not rotate, but instead head straight towards the SOUL; the spears travel in the direction they were initially facing for a few seconds before fading away.</string>
    <string name="undyneBattleDesc">Undyne main attacks are spears and turn the protagonist\'s soul green, making them unable to move and forcing them to \'face\' the dangers while protecting with a shield.\n\nThe actions available are FIGHT, ACT or MERCY\nMERCY menu has spare and flee. Spare does nothing while Flee allows you to run away from the battle if your soul is red. Now in the overworld you can run from her, but she will eventually catch you and you\'ll have to repeat the flee. You can successfully escape from her running to Hotland, where she couldn\'t be due her armor being too hot.\n\nIf we FIGHT her, she will continue attacking very slow while her body melts. If the genocide route is active, she will turn into Undyne the Undying\n\nIn the ACT menu, the option are Check;that gives us a description of her, like usual, Plead; trying multiple times allows to have less extreme attacks, and Challenge. Depending of what the box says, spears comes in a lower speed, a higher or in a extreme speed.</string>
    <string name="undyneDeterminationAttack">Not like Amalgamates, but her own character and determination to protect everyone allows her to have Determination, but in a lower level than the protagonist. In the Neutral route can be seen if we low her HP to 0, but her body, unable to keep that Determination, ends melting after a few attack turns. If Genocide route is active, she won\'t melt and instead turn into Undyne the Undying</string>
    <string name="determinationPalabra">Determination</string>

    <string name="sansApparence">Sans appears as a short, paunchy skeleton with a wide toothy grin, glove-like hands and large eye sockets. He wears an unzipped blue hoodie, a white shirt, black shorts with white lining, and a pair of slippers. He has white pupils that disappear when he is serious or angered. When Sans uses telekinesis, his left eye flashes light blue and yellow, the colors for patience and justice, and his right pupil disappears.</string>
    <string name="sansPersonality">Sans is laid back and flippant, often sleeping on the job and taking breaks. His laziness is a combination of fatalism and apathy. He wonders if his indolence stems from his knowledge that any progress he makes will be erased when the timeline resets. Conversely, he suggests that this knowledge could be \"a poor excuse for being lazy.\"On the other hand, when Papyrus becomes the leader in the Papyrus ending, Sans is implied to be working harder despite not denying his laziness upon being called out on it. This is because while Sans is apathetic towards life, he is never apathetic towards the people he cares about.\n\nThough Sans is usually agreeable, he becomes eerily serious at particular moments. He is also observant; Sans reads the protagonist\'s expressions and can often tell when they have already done certain tasks. He enjoys making various strange jokes that tend to involve pranks and things that just mess with people\'s heads, such as \"selling fried snow\" which on its own makes no sense, but then raising the price to ludicrous degrees until saying he does not want to sell it because it has \"too much sentimental value.\" His pranks involve juvenile things such as eye paint on a telescope, an unscrewed ketchup bottle, and whoopee cushions. He occasionally makes some low-brow puns and the fact that he performs at the MTT Resort hints that he may be a talented comedian. He enjoys science fiction and loves to drink ketchup.He also hates making promises.This is possibly because he seems unable to stick to his own moral compass as he congratulates the protagonist on keeping this idea in their heart, but he does everything in his power to kill the protagonist by any means necessary during the Genocide Route, even faking mercy on them. This is supported by the fact Sans is clearly not afraid of killing when he mentions to the protagonist that if \"the old lady\" had not made him promise to protect them, \"(they\'d) be dead where (they) stand.\" He does show incredible restraint however, as he never tries to fight the protagonist even if they kill the people closest to him, only outwardly shaming them with disturbing implications about their character and direct judgement on their actions, coldly asking them \"Then why\'d you kill my brother?\" or calling them a dirty brother killer. His pledge to this promise even goes so deep that if Papyrus is killed but not Toriel, he does not mention the protagonist\'s slaughter to Toriel in order to not emotionally damage her.\n\nSans may have a scientific background. Evidence includes the quantum physics book, workshop, his relationship to Alphys,affinity for science,his inexplicable ability to teleport and his timeline research.\n\nSans offhandedly mentions to the protagonist that he understands that they would \"want to go back\" and suggests that they already have everything they could need. He seems to be longing and searching for a life that he cannot go back to as he \"gave up trying to go back a long time ago\" and as a Lost Soul tells the protagonist that \"you\'ll never see \'em again.\" He is implied to have given up on trying to go back as he had projected acceptance in staying in this new life to the protagonist, although what Sans is trying to go back to is quite vague.</string>
    <string name="sansHistoria">Sans introduces himself to the protagonist in Snowdin Forest after he initially appears as a silhouette. He explains that he has no interest in capturing humans, but that his brother, Papyrus, does. Then, Sans hides the protagonist behind a lamp whose shape is identical to the protagonist\'s. Papyrus rushes onscreen, and the brothers discuss Sans\'s laziness and the importance of puzzle upkeep. Sans appears multiple times throughout Snowdin Forest, observing and commentating on the puzzles but not engaging in any japery, except for the word search.\n\nBefore Papyrus\'s battle, Sans is absent in Snowdin Town. He appears briefly to play trombone during the date/hangout with Papyrus but does not appear again until the Last Corridor if the protagonist kills Papyrus.</string>
    <string name="bonesPalabra">Bones</string>
    <string name="blueSoulAttack">He turns your soul to blue and you can now access to his blue attacks. Being blue means your soul is affected by gravity and blue attacks mean to stay still in order to not receive damage from them</string>

    <string name="papyrusApparence">Papyrus is a tall, perhaps anatomically inaccurate skeleton, with a skull more vertical and geometric than his brother. Being skeletal, many of his expressions incorporate a toothy grin. His eyes resemble vertical slits; his skeletal pseudo-brows form most of his expressions, as well as the corners of his mouth. He has eyeballs which show at times when he is experiencing strong emotions.</string>
    <string name="papyrusPersonality">Papyrus is a flamboyant skeleton who presents a confident, charismatic image of himself. He works hard and, despite his brash personality, is kind at heart. He is optimistic, brave, and considerate even when the protagonist beheads him in the Genocide Route. He is also occasionally oblivious and nonobservant, but can be cunning at times, as seen when he uses reverse psychology to trick Undyne into befriending the protagonist. He shows great bravery as even in the face of potentially imminent death, he drops his guard and spares the protagonist in hopes of driving them down a better path.</string>
</resources>